音标等于数学记号。如果你能接受 2 乘以 2 可以
Phonetic transcription equals mathematical notation. If you accept that 2 times 2 can
写成 2 squared，那你就能接受同一个概念有多个标签。
also be written 2 squared, you're comfortable with multiple labels for a
这和 cat 这个词也可以写成 k-a-t、cat，是同一个原则。
single concept. This is the same principle as the word cat, also being written as k
同一个概念。这和 cat 也可以写成 k-a-t、cat 是同一个原则。
digraph a t, cat. Here's a simple two-part rule for the letter O. One. In a one
单音节词中，O 通常读作 ah，除非词尾是 E：hot、lost、tom、bob、
-syllable word, O sounds like ah, unless the word ends in E. hot, lost, tom, bob,
dot com。第二，在重读音节中，O 也读作 ah：possible、Holland、
dot com. Two, in a stress syllable, O also sounds like ah. Possible, Holland,
philosophy。下面是字母 A 的两条规则：第一，在单音节词里，A
philosophy. Here's a two-part rule for the letter A. One, in a one-syllable word, A
通常读作 ah，除非词尾是 E：cat、Sam、drab。第二，在重读音节中，
sounds like ah, unless the word ends in E. Cat, Sam, drab. Two, in a stress syllable,
A 读作 ah。听这些例词。
A sounds like ah. functional, manager, catastrophe. Once you've internalized the
内化这些基本音标规则后，你需要勤奋、持续、甚至顽固地
basic rules of phonetics, you need to diligently, persistently, and stubbornly
并普遍应用它们。用计算机术语说，可以把它想成一次全局搜索，
apply them universally. In computing terms, think of doing a global search all
并替换。有些人一开始排斥读音标，因为它
and replace. Some people have an initial aversion to reading phonetics because it's
既新鲜又令人困惑，甚至看起来不像英语。这里正是我们要让你
new and confusing. It doesn't even look like English. This is where we're going to
练习开放心态和信任的地方；区别在于，如果你
have you practice some of that open-mindedness and trust, except that if you
读音标，就会有美国口音。有位会计师
read the phonetics, you will have an American accent. An accountant kept making
在英语里一次又一次犯同样的发音错误；问她为什么时，她
the same pronunciation errors in English over and over again, asked why, her
总是回答：我忘了。有人问她是不是忘了算术，她回答：
response was consistently, I forgot. When asked if she forgot arithmetic, the answer
“当然不会，那会让我日子很难过。”真正的问题是
was, well, of course not, that would make my life miserable. Well, not applying the
音标规则才真正让她日子难过。
phonetics was making her life miserable.